boden.co.uk 2009-05-19

# Privacy policy

As with all shopping websites, we collect personal information from you when you shop online at Boden.co.uk or Bodenusa.com

We use this information to make your shopping experience as easy and enjoyable as possible. We need it to process your order, inform you of any delays or problems and occasionally to send you special offers and promotions.

The information we collect is:

  * Your name – so we know what to call you
  * Email address – so we can email you order confirmations, delivery delays, offers etc
  * Delivery address – an obvious one
  * Telephone number – we’ll only call if we have a delivery problem
  * Credit card details – we only ask for these when you place an order 

We use the latest secure server technology to ensure this information is protected to the highest standards. 

We use encryption to safeguard your credit card information and only accept orders from web browsers that permit communication through Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology \- this means you cannot inadvertently place an order through an unsecured connection. Most web browsers above version three support this security. 

This encryption makes it virtually impossible for unauthorised parties to read any information that you send us. 

The encryption technique we use is the highest standard available for e-commerce and certified by VeriSign, the world's most respected certification body for Internet firms. 

All orders are then processed on computers that are not connected to the Internet. 

##  Data Protection

  * Boden is a registered data user under the Data Protection Act. We will never pass on your details on to a third party for marketing purposes. We will however send you details of offers from other companies that we think may interest you, but only with your permission. If you would like to receive such offers please email [ optin@boden.co.uk](mailto:optin@boden.co.uk).   

There are only four circumstances where we may share some of your data with others:

  * With agents (including credit reference agencies, credit card clearing agencies (Barclays Merchant Services in UK and Payment Tech in USA), fraud prevention and detection agencies) that we use to process the orders you place with us or who assist us in the service we provide to you. In these instances, we provide them with only the information they need to perform their function
  * In the unlikely event that our business assets are ever sold to or purchased by another company. (Our data records are part of our business). 
  * To outside research companies whom we may ask to contact you directly for your opinions on our products and services (in which case we provide them with only the information they need to perform their function). 
  * We do occasionally make names and addresses (but never email addresses) available to companies whose products we think may interest you, unless you have told us not to. If you do not wish to receive such offers please email us at [ mailingoptout@boden.co.uk](mailto:mailingoptout@boden.co.uk) with your account number, which can be found above your address on you latest catalogue. 

If you have questions about your personal data or our privacy policy, please contact us at [privacy@boden.co.uk](mailto:privacy@boden.co.uk)

You’ll also find more information about this in our  Security FAQs section.

To see all the information we have about you, and to correct any inaccuracies, please write to:   
The Data Protection Officer  
JP Boden & Co Ltd.   
Boden House  
114-120 Victoria Road   
London  
UK   
NW10 6NY

##  Cookies

Cookies are small text files that websites send to your computer. A cookie can be thought of as an Internet user's identification card. They let the website know when the user has returned. This lets the site bring up information relevant to that user, for example your name, past orders etc.

Cookies make the interaction between users and websites faster and easier. Without cookies, it would be very difficult for a website to allow a visitor to fill up a shopping basket or to remember the user's preferences or registration details for a future visit. The Boden website uses cookies to allow customers to move from one part of the web site to another and to add items to the shopping basket without having to login repeatedly.

Cookies are not computer programs, and can't read other information saved on your hard drive. They cannot be used to disseminate viruses, or get a user's email address etc. They only contain and transfer to the website as much information as the users themselves have disclosed to that website.

##  Data over the Internet 

We use a third-party service provider to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet and sometimes on this site. They may collect anonymous information about your visits to our Web site, and your interaction with our products and services. They may also use information about your visits to this and other Web sites to target advertisements for goods and services. This anonymous information is collected through the use of a pixel tag, which is industry standard technology used by most major web sites. No personally identifiable information is collected or used in this process. They do not know the name, phone number, address, email address, or any personally identifying information about the user. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this anonymous information used by our third party service provider, please visit [our third party service provider’s website](http://acerno.com/privacy.html).

You can also read more about online marketing practices and the technologies that support them by visiting the[ Network Advertising Initiative’s website](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).
